Engr. S Krishnan Sinnappan Lot 1040, Lorong Dataran B, College Height Garden Resort, 71700 Mantin, Negeri Sembilan, Malaysia

Email: krishnan_ss2005@yahoo.co.uk

H/P No.: 006-012-755 4122



Dear Sir / Madam,

I am 42 years of age and in excellent health. I have a Bachelor of Engineering, Honors degree in Electrical & Electronics Engineering field from University of East London and also pursued my Master of Science in Telecommunications System Engineering there. My particulars are shown in my resume which is enclosed for your kind perusal. I thoroughly enjoyed my work here but I am looking for a change of employment which would widen my experience and horizon. I believe that a well known organization such as yours might be able to use my talent and skills as I have much to offer, and together we may grow to greater heights.

I had worked in Panasonic Research & Development Centre, Panasonic AVC Networks Malaysia for the twelve years and tendered my resignation because I want a change and new challenges in my work. I believe my practical knowledge, skills and qualifications will prove to be useful in meeting the demands and challenges of the global employment market as I have the experience and expertise in the said field hence, I joined the education filed and joined UCSI University since December 2010.

My last held post in Panasonic Research & Development Centre, Panasonic AVC Networks Malaysia was as an Assistant General Manager, in charge of 96 engineers. My principal role was to develop SMPS (Switching Mode Power Supply) and Key Modules (CD, MD, DVD, DVDR, SD player, USB, Optical Pick-Unit) and develop Panasonic Home Theater Systems/ Hi-fi Systems with my team. Besides developing the above, I have to ensure that the transfer of new products from design to the production department is handled smoothly. In addition, I have to transfer the technology involved and information to the QA Department and Production Engineering Department regarding new technology and problems pertaining to the quality of products made. Besides that, I also provide support to our customers and sub contractors. The products developed by my team are marketed worldwide in Japan, Canada, US, Europe and in Asian countries.

Then, I embarked into the field of education when I joined UCSI University in December 2010 as I wanted to impart my knowledge in electrical and electronics engineering to the young generation. I was assigned to teach Electromagnetic Theory I for year two students and have successfully completed four terms to date. I also taught a semester of Electromagnetic Theory II to year three students and three semesters of Communication Circuit to year three students too. In addition, I taught two semesters on fibre optics for fourth year final students and one semester of Advanced Circuit theory and Transmission lines to year two students. Besides, I was also in charge of the final year projects for final year students

Then, I joined Summit Edu Constatncy as Business Development Director. My main task is to identifying business opportunities for the organization and managing key client relationships.

In addition to the above particulars and those enclosed in my CV, I strongly believe that I make a suitable candidate. I hope my application will be given due consideration and I will be looking forward to your favourable reply. Thanking you in advance for your kind co-operation.

Thank you. Yours truly, S Krishnan Sinnappan

PERSONAL PARTICULARS

Name : Engr. S Krishnan Sinnappan

Address : No 1040, Lorong dataran B,

College Heights Garden Resort 71700 Mantin, Negeri Sembilan,

Malaysia

Current Location : (As Per Address Above) / Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Tel. : +6 012 755 4122

Email Add. : krishnan_ss2005@yahoo.co.uk

Date of Birth : 16^{th} April 1972

Nationality : Malaysian

Marital Status : Married

Years of Experience : Director & Consultant (Education & Training) : 1 Year

University Lecturer (Engineering Faculty) : 2 Years
Asst. Gen. Manager (Panasonic R&D Centre) : 12 Years

Availability Date : 1st Aug 2014

SUMMARY

A self initiated, motivated, team playing, task oriented and organized person coupled with excellent management skills. The incumbent is backed by more than 12 years of technical knowledge in the Consumer industry with a prominent and established multi-national employer. The incumbent within the span of twelve years with the Company has been promoted to various levels of positions up to the present as Asst. General Manager in the Research and Development Department of the organization. In this position the incumbent has charge over 7 Managers, 8 Senior Engineers, 14 Engineers and 67 Junior Engineers. In the various positions held by the incumbent, the incumbent has proactively contributed to the growth of the Research and Development Centre and in particular has contributed inter alia, to the creation of PMX 2 a micro compo which is marketed worldwide and which is the number 1 selling audio product in Germany and SC-PM770 also a micro compo which achieved number 1 selling product in Japan. In addition the incumbent has also played a pivotal role in the creation & development of the SMPS (Switching Mode Power Supply) and Key Modules (CD, MD, DVD, DVDR, SD player, USB, Optical Pick-up Unit) which has been successfully launched and marketed worldwide. The incumbent is comfortable operating in a lean system of organization and has the ability to turn around departments to fit such form of operating system. The incumbent is able to operate in any kind of organization - hierarchical, flat, central or de-centralized. Being a solution oriented person the incumbent's ability to meet challenge with stride and ability to handle stress and human capital value adds to any organization.

The incumbent is a person who is known amongst superiors and peers as a person who is able to perform beyond the output required and within short deadlines.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Summit Edu Consultancy Business Development Director & Consultant– Jun 2013 – Present

The incumbent worked in a capacity as a Business Development Director and consultant which entailed pursuing sales leads and prospective clients, delivering presentations and proposals, and negotiating and closing business deals; developing business plans that include marketing strategies; maintaining extensive knowledge of current market conditions and reporting this to key staff; and building and maintaining important client relationships.

UCSI University Lecturer – Dec 2010 – Dec 2012

The incumbent is a lecturer in the Engineering department and had taught the following subjects besides carrying out all other duties that entails the job of a lecturer.

The notable accomplishments in this position have been the teaching and tutoring of year two students in the field of Electromagnetic Theory I and Electromagnetic Theory II to year three students. The incumbent also taught Communication Circuit to year three students and Fibre Optics for fourth year final students. Besides teaching Advanced Circuit theory and Transmission lines to year two students, the incumbent was in charge of the final year projects for the final year students. The incumbent also was one of the committee members for the M.Sc. student selection committee and supervised their work.

PANASONIC AVC NETWORKS, JOHOR, MALAYSIA

Assistant General Manager - Dec 2008 - Feb 2010

The incumbent is the Head of Department of the Malaysian venture and reports direct to the Audio Video Business Unit R&D Director based in Japan and Senior Management of the Company. In this portfolio the incumbent has to submit weekly reports on the status of all the R&D activities which has been allocated to the unit.

Notable accomplishments in this position have been:

- 1. Successfully created technical documents for new features of new models testing in particular SMPS, USB, SD Ripping, IPOD, Bluetooth, High Speed Recording and is at present being marketed worldwide as SC-PM770, SC-EN38 and NS- 570 to name a few.
- 2. Created and established new model development flow for the department which is presently being used by Panasonic Mexico and Brazil.
- 3. Worked together with the Patent Agents in drafting patent specifications for the obtainment of patents for the new products that are produced.
- 4. Successfully assisted in claiming for the company through the double taxation relief for a figure of approximately RM6 million and at present working to claim a proposed amount of RM16 million. The incumbent is able to make the R&D department not a wholly cost incurring department of the organization.
- 5. On the management front, the management costing is captured with an accurate time driven activity based costing which does not only depict the actual cost but provides the actual breakdown which assist the company in their pricing and marketing endeavours and made the R&D department more efficient in terms of performance and has successfully instilled the culture of work performance based department to manage costing. This made market re-works to be reduced by 71%.
- 6. Established and implemented career planning systems for the development of the human capital within the department.

Research and Development Department

Senior Manager - 2006 ~ 2008

The incumbent was heading the Key Device and Electrical and Electronics Section. In this portfolio the incumbent reported to Department Director. In this position the incumbent inter alia, reviewed design schedule of new product development from initial mock-up right up to ship out; successfully catered for the acceptance of the design transfer from the designing phase to the development section; obtainment of the approval prior to the mass production stage of the particular product which has passed the development stage; managed and handled a department with a manpower base of 52 engineers; other routine activities such as daily activity, technical discussions, preparation of weekly reports for both top management at the company level and HQ level, preparation of budget for the following financial year; calculation, review and tabling of proposed new model development costs for the tabling for the next financial year business plan and high level research and development in accordance to the direction of the company and vision.

Notable accomplishments, inter alia, in this portfolio:

- 1. Developed the first Switching Mode Power Supply & Secure Digital ripping home theatre system, which has been successfully marketed in Europe and Japan;
- 2. Developed the first Rack Theatre System which was to expand the company's line of product range which made the company the first movers of such system and has become a number 1 selling product in Japan; and
- 3. Developed R&D Skill Evolution system which is used as one of the Key Performance Indicators for the purpose of remuneration and development of the work force.

Manager - 2004 ~ 2006

Was in charge of Key Device Division and was reporting to the Department Director. Primarily was dealing with design of CD, MD, DVD, USB modules. Handled costing, design and the preparation of yearly road-map (the forecast of the next financial year activities) together with the production of the schedules and required budgeting to assist the Head of Department to prepare a budget report to be presented to the top management for the next financial year.

Notable accomplishments, *inter alia*, in this portfolio:

- 1. Successfully spearheaded the designing and development of high speed CD to MD recording modules;
- 2. Designed and developed USB modules together with the semiconductor subsidiary company within the Group of Companies; and
- 3. Implemented cost down activities which has helped to maintain a low costing of the division.

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Asst Manager, 2002~2003 Senior Engineer, 2001 ~ 2002 Engineer, 1999 ~ 2000 Junior Engineer, 1998 ~ 1998

EDUCATION HISTORY

University of East London, UK Master of Science, Telecommunications, 1997

University of East London, UK

Bachelor of Engineering (Hons), Electrical and Electronic Engineering, 1996

Midas Inst. of Engeeneering Technology

Diploma in Electrical and Electronic Engineering, 1993

University of Oxford Delegacy of Local Examinations, Singapore Certificate, Information Technology, Autocad Release 11, 1993

LANGUAGES

Spoken/Fluent : English, Bahasa Malaysia, Tamil

Written : English, Bahasa Malaysia, Tamil

TECHNICAL SKILLS / CERTIFICATIONS

Management Training : Problem Solving and Decision Making Skills

: Managing for Success

: Matsushita Business Philosophy: Total Quality Management Training

: Documenting & Implementing an ISO9001:2000 QMS

: Internal Audit By Process Approach

: Product & Process Innovation: Communicating With Presence

: Course Analysis Techniques For Manufacturing Personnel Course: Aim For the Stars, Shoot From Heart (Panasonic Philosophy)

Technical Training : Huawei Optical Communication (Train-the-Trainer)

: Introduction of LABVIEW

: Remote Sensing & Communication Satellite Network

: Image Compression (JPEG)

: Fundamental of DVD Technology

Award : Panasonic Long Service Award (10Years)

: Panasonic Long Service Award (5 Years)

Appreciation : Committee & Invigilator

15th Malaysia Matsushita Group Technical Skill Competition

: Committee & Invigilator

14th Malaysia Matsushita Group Technical Skill Competition

Others :

Extremely well versed with MS Office, Internet, EMC measurement tools, AUDIO Precision tools, CADIX (PCB pattern drawing software), SFX (schematic drawing software), possess the ability and know-how to detect with 100% accuracy flaws within the digital amplifying design.

Other softwares include, AutoCAD, CADStar, Protel, CADIX - PCB Design, HSPICE - Electronic Simulator, ECAD - VLSI Design, Work Bench - Electronic Design/Simulation and others.

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

- i) MIET (Member of Engineering Technology, UK)
- ii) IEM (Institute of Engineering Malaysia)
- iii) Registered with Board of Engineers, Malaysia

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Possess **Persons of Indian Origin Card (PIO)** which allows the incumbent to visit India without a need for application of Visas.

In possession of United States of America Business Trip Visa which is valid till 2014.

For Further Reference, please contact

Mr. Sarveswaran Karunanithi Lecturer University Tenaga National

Email: sarveswaren@yahoo.com

Ms Cecilia Anthony Dass Lecturer

Curtin University, Malaysia

Email: ceciliaanthony@hotmail.com